Finding aid for University Herbarium (University of Michigan) Records, 1744-1745, 1851-1981, and 2001-2014
Bentley Historical Library
- Bartlett, Harley Harris, 1744-1855; 1875-1959
  - Correspondence and Associated Materials, 1875-1959
    - W
      - Walker, Egbert H., 1940-1945 (Box 18)
        (A.F. collecting; ASTP; Company D, etc.; see Ammann, G.A., Special Interests-Plant Collecting A.F.)
      - Walker, Egbert H., 1946-1949 (Box 18)
        (China flora project; A.F. collecting)
      - Walker, Egbert H., 1950-1958 (Box 18)
      - Walker, H.B., 1947 (Box 18)
      - Walkinshaw, 1950 (Box 18)
      - Walkom, Arthur B., 1929 (Box 18)
        (coals & shales)
      - Waller, Adolph, 1941-1952 (Box 18)
      - Walp, Russell Lee, 1928-1952 (Box 18)
      - Walpole, Branson A., 1921 (Box 18)
        (Mich. Acad.)
      - Walter, Erich A., 1938-1956 (Box 18)
      - Walton, C.F., 1936; 1946-1949 (Box 18)
        (re Sam GranickWang, Lucy C., Hwa Nan College; Ruth Chan; see)
      - Wang, Lucy C., 1946-1949 (Box 18)
        (Hwa Nan College; Ruth Chan)
      - Wang, Yun-Chang, 1949 (Box 18)
        (fellowship application)
      - Wannamaker, Olin D., 1946 (Box 18)
        (China flora)
      - War-related activities, 1936-1948
        - Army Specialized Train Program, East Asia Area & Language, 1944-1946 (Box 18)
        - Armed Forces -- Collecting, 1944-1946 (Box 18)
          (30 items)
        - Civil Affairs Training Schools, Far Eastern Area (Company A) 17 items-correspondence, 1944 (Box 18)
        - Civil Affairs Training Schools, Far Eastern Area programs, lecture notes, report (Box 18)
        - Company D, 1946-48, 1961 (Box 18)
          ("Newsletter"; correspondence with members; A.F. collecting; see Walker, E.H.)
        - U.S. Naval Intelligence Service, 1944 (Box 18)
        - U.S. War Department, 1936-1947 (Box 18)
      - War-related-miscellaneous (Box 18)
      - Ward, Marcus (Box 18)
        (see University Club)
      - Ward, R. Gerard, 1958 (Box 18)
      - Warnock, Barton H., 1949 (Box 18)
        (Parthenium argentatum)
      - Warren, Paul A., 1922-1930 (Box 18)
      - Warren, Stanley W., 1947 (Box 18)
      - Washburn, E.R., 1928 (Box 18)
        (wood from oil wells)
      - Washington Academy of Sciences, 1927; 1946 (Box 18)
      - Washington Biologists' Field Club (Box 18)
      - Watkins, Herbert G., 1928-1948 (Box 18)
        (administrative-U of M Regents)
      - Watkins, James M. (Box 18)
        (see U.S.D.A.-For. Agr. Rels.)
      - Watson, Edwardo H., 1930-1931 (Box 18)
        ("botanical notes")
      - Watson, Elba E., 1928 (Box 18)
      - Watters, Kenneth L., 1956 (Box 18)
      - Watters, R.F., 1959 (Box 18)
      - Wear, John F., 1945 (Box 18)
      - Weatherby, Charles A., 1925-1945 (Box 18)
        (see also Chase, E.W.B. (Photograph Album))
      - Weatherwax, Paul, 1933 (Box 18)
      - Webb, H.A., 1936 (Box 18)
        (opportunities for H.S. teachers)
      - Weber, Harry F., 1948-1949 (Box 18)
        (Scholarships-Seoul; Chung In Cho)
      - Weber, W.M., 1950 (Box 18)
        (Aleutians-birds)
      - Webster, Grady L., 1949-1956 (Box 18)
      - Wee, Lim D., 1945 (Box 18)
      - Weetman, G.F., 1956 (Box 18)
      - Wehmeyer, Lewis E., 1925-1937 (Box 18)
        (collecting of Ascomycetous fungi)
      - Weidman, R.H., 1945 (Box 18)
      - Weier, Thomas Elliot, 1928-1942 (Box 18)
        (student, positions, etc.)
      - Wein, K., 1933 (Box 18)
      - Weldon, Robert H., 1945 (Box 18)
      - Wells, Bertram Whittier, 1936-1940 (Box 18)
      - Wells, Carlton, 1958 (Box 18)
        (Barbour Scholarship)
      - Wenner-Gren Foundation, 1954-1956 (Box 18)
        (Fire & Prim. Agr.; student expeditions)
      - Went, Frits W., 1932 (Box 18)
      - West, 1959 (Box 18)
      - West, Gladys F., 1928-1938 (Box 18)
      - West, Robert C., 1957 (Box 18)
      - Westerman, J.H., 1957 (Box 19)
      - Weston, William H., 1940-1946 (Box 19)
        (re students)
      - Westphal, Maxine, 1949 (Box 19)
      - Wetmore, Alexander, 1926-1951 (Box 19)
        (see also: Smithsonian Inst.)
      - Whaley, W. Gordon, 1939-1946 (Box 19)
        (position; U.S.D.A.-B.P.I.-Rubber)
      - Wharton, Mary E., 1937-1946 (Box 19)
        (student-Mississippian;)
      - Wheeler, W.M., 1918 (Box 19)
        (ants)
      - Wherry, Edgar T., 1926; 1933 (Box 19)
        (Iris lacustris, Oenothera)
      - Whitaker, D.M., 1945 (Box 19)
      - Whitaker, Judith P.M., 1945 (Box 19)
      - White, Alfred H., 1939 (Box 19)
        (Acanthus)
      - White, Cyril T. (Box 19)
        (see Herbarium: Exch. & Loans-Australia)
      - White, David (Box 19)
        (shales; see National Research Council & U.S. Dept. Int.-Geological Survey)
      - White, F. Arnold, 1943-1944 (Box 19)
        (rubber investigations; guayule-Chile)
      - White, George H., 1953 (Box 19)
      - White, George O., 1954 (Box 19)
        (bit trees)
      - White, Leslie A., 1936 (Box 19)
        (East Indies)
      - White, Stephen S., 1938 (Box 19)
        (student-collector)
      - White, Wallace H. (Box 19)
      - Whitehouse, W.E. (Box 19)
        (see U.S.D.A.-B.P.I.-Plant Exploration & Introduction)
      - White's Woods, 1945 (Box 19)
        (loss to University)
      - Whiting, Alfred F., 1941 (Box 19)
      - Whitney Foundation, 1954 (Box 19)
        (lecturing)
      - Whittemore, Harlow O., 1940-1950 (Box 19)
      - Whittlesey, Derwent, 1955 (Box 19)
      - "Who Knows, and What", 1950 (Box 19)
        (see Marquis Co.)
      - Whyte, R.O., 1957 (Box 19)
      - Wiebe, G.A. (Box 19)
        (see U.S. Dept. Agr., Agr. Res. Admin.)
      - Wiechers, Enrique, 1947 (Box 19)
      - Wieland, George R., 1928-1929 (Box 19)
        (N.R.C. Fellowships)
      - Wiggins, Ira L., 1944-1950 (Box 19)
        (28 yrs with Douglas Houghton)
      - Wilbur, Robert L., 1949-1950 (Box 19)
      - Wilcox, Harry H., Jr., 1945 (Box 19)
        (A.F. collecting; Philippines)
      - Wild Flower Preservation Society, invitation to lecture (Box 19)
      - Wildman, Sam G., 1941-1944 (Box 19)
        (student; rubber investigation)
      - John Wiley & Sons, 1932; 1946 (Box 19)
        (botany texts)
      - Wilimovsky, Norman J., 1945 (Box 19)
      - Wilkinson, H.R., 1956 (Box 19)
      - Wilkinson, R.G., 1936 (Box 19)
        (Malay)
      - Wilkinson, R.J., 1926 (Box 19)
        (Evolution)
      - Willey, John W., 1950 (Box 19)
        (Philippines, wood, grass)
      - Williams, E.M. (Box 19)
        (see War-related activities-Company D)
      - Williams, Mrs. F.R. (Box 19)
        (see Herb Society of America)
      - Williams, J.S., 1938 (Box 19)
      - Williams, Llewelyn, 1959 (Box 19)
        (tropical woods)
      - Williams, Robert L., 1938-1954 (Box 19)
        ("titling of employees"; Japanese botanical books)
      - Williams, T.J., 1943 (Box 19)
        (Trithrinax in Cordoba; Map; 18 photographs, photographs-Argentina)
      - Williams, Wade L., 1946 (Box 19)
      - Willison, Malcolm, 1958-1959 (Box 19)
        ("Malayan words in English")
      - Wilson, Adrian P., 1950 (Box 19)
      - Wilson, James P., 1943-1944 (Box 19)
        (fellowships)
      - Winchester, John R., 1945 (Box 19)
      - Winzerling, Harry W., 1932 (Box 19)
      - Wissler, Clark, 1936 (Box 19)
      - Wolff, Emily T., 1944 (Box 19)
        (identification of fibers)
      - Wolff, Simon E., 1934; 1945 (Box 19)
        (Compositae of Michigan; A.F.)
      - Woman Citizen, 1912 (Box 19)
      - Wong, Cheong-yin, 1939-1940 (Box 19)
        (China colleges)
      - Wood, Chinese books (Box 19)
      - Wood, Grace Louise, 1948-1950 (Box 19)
        (fellowship, Philippine anthropology)
      - Wood, G.H.S., 1956 (Box 19)
      - Wood, Harold C. (Box 19)
      - Wood, William R., 1948 (Box 19)
        (Philippine schools)
      - Woodburne, Lloyd S., 1942-1950 (Box 19)
      - Woodbury, C.G., 1929 (Box 19)
        (recommendation for honorary degree for J.B. Howard)
      - Woodbury, Richard B., 1958 (Box 19)
      - Woodson, Robert E., 1932-1933 (Box 19)
        (Apocynaceae; Asclepiadaceae)
      - Woollett, Marjorie L., 1929 (Box 19)
      - Woolston, William C., 1942 (Box 19)
        (medical student)
      - Works, George A., 1945 (Box 19)
        (vegetational mapping)
      - Wrather, W.E. (Box 19)
        (see U.S. Dept. Int.-Geolog. Surv.)
      - Wright, Jonathan W., 1945 (Box 19)
      - Wright, Quincy, 1956 (Box 19)
        (over-population)
      - Wright, Willard H., 1947 (Box 19)
        (Fulbright funds; Philippines)
      - Wu, Ching-Yi (Box 19)
      - Wurfel, Violet E., 1947 (Box 19)
        (Fulbright, U. Philippines)
      - Wyatt-Smith, J., 1959 (Box 19)
      - Wybornow, J. & D., 1946 (Box 19)
      - Wyman, Donald, 1947 (Box 19)
        ("Arboretums & Botanical Gardens)
    - Y
      - Yabes, Leopoldo Y., 1936-1937 (Box 19)
        (Linguistics)
      - Yakely, Elida, 1938 (Box 19)
      - Yamada-Kindi, 1927-1937 (Box 19)
      - Yamamoto, Yoshimatsu, 1928-1934 (Box 19)
      - Yang, Yu-Teh, 1944 (Box 19)
      - Yarman, Alexander J., 1945 (Box 19)
      - Yates, H.S., 1927-1933 (Box 19)
      - Yelland Photographic Prints (Box 19)
        (see Berkeley Photographic Prints)
      - Yoakum, Clarence S., 1936-1946 (Box 19)
        (personnel, research funds, admin. Graduate School; see also Pavetti-Morin, War-related CATS)
      - Yoder, David I., 1940 (Box 19)
      - Yoder, Henry O., 1957 (Box 19)
      - Yoder, Ray A., 1958 (Box 19)
      - York, C.L., A.F. collecting (Box 19)
      - Yorman, A.J., 1945 (Box 19)
      - Young, Edward L., 1944-1945 (Box 19)
      - Young, R.A. (Box 19)
        (see U.S.D.A.-B.P.I.-Plant Exploration & Introduction, & Foreign Seed & Plant Introduction)
      - Youtie, H.C., linguistics (Box 19)
      - Yuncker, Truman George, 1921-1951 (Box 19)
        (plant collections, etc.)
      - Yung, Chi-tung, 1944 (Box 19)
        (re Chan, Sui-tong)
    - Z
      - Zalewski, Boleslaw, 1929 (Box 19)
        (position-student)
      - Zebrowski, George, 1936-1938 (Box 19)
        (manuscripts; see also Sparrow, F.K.)
      - Zeigler, George A., 1944 (Box 19)
        (bamboo)
      - Zetek, James, 1940; 1950 (Box 19)
      - Ziesenheime, Rudolf, 1946 (Box 19)
        (A.F. collecting; begonias)
      - Zimmerman, Dale A., 1949 (Box 19)
      - Zinderen Bakker, E.M. Van, 1957 (Box 19)
      - Zingg, Robert M., 1932 (Box 19)
        (Malay plant names; anthropology)
      - Zirkle, Conway, 1946 (Box 19)
        (re Isadore Cohen)
      - Zwerdling, Osias & Hannah, 1936; 1939 (Box 19)
        (mortgage)
      - Zwickey, A. Lynn, 1936 (Box 19)
        (student-ethnobotany)
  - Family Correspondence, 1909-1913
    Family Correspondence, 1909-1913 (0.8 linear feet), arranged chronologically, is a series of correspondence with Bartlett's parents and sister. (donated by the University Herbarium)
    - Family Correspondence, 1909-1913 (Box 19)
    - Letters to Mr. and Mrs. J.H. Bartlett and Hazel, February 1909-January 1910; 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Letters to Mr. and Mrs. J.H. Bartlett, October 1912-December 1912; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Letters to Mr. and Mrs. J.H. Bartlett, October 1912-November 1913 (Box 19)
    - Letters to Mr. and Mrs. J.H. Bartlett, December 1912-November 1913; 5 folders (Box 20)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1904-1915
    Personal Correspondence, 1904-1915 (0.6 linear feet), arranged alphabetically, consists of Bartlett's personal correspondence as an undergraduate at Harvard and during his time at the Bureau. (This portion of the collection was donated by the University of Virginia Mountain Home Biological Station)
    The personal correspondence includes a series of correspondence from genetics pioneer Hugo de Vries regarding plant switching, the effects of World War I on botanical research, and de Vries travels in the United States. The subseries also includes correspondence with Arthur Stanley Pease, an amateur botanist and future president of Amherst College. Additional correspondence with Pease is located in the Correspondence and Associated Material series.
    - Bartlett, Clifford, 1904-1906 (Box 20)
    - Bartlett, Hazel, 1904-1906 (Box 20)
    - Bartlett, Jonathan, 1904-1906 (Box 20)
    - Cousin Helen, 1904 (Box 20)
    - Crane, Robert E., 1906 (Box 20)
    - de Vries, Hugo (plant specimen), 1912-1915 (Box 20)
    - Douglass, Benjamin W., 1904-1906 (Box 20)
    - Friend, Edwin W., 1905-1906 (Box 20)
    - Francis, C.J., 1906 (Box 20)
    - Grandma, 1904-1906 (Box 20)
    - Henninger, Carl, 1904-1905 (Box 20)
    - Marion, 1904-1906 (Box 20)
    - Mathews, J. Schuyler, 1914 (Box 20)
    - Matthews, J.D., 1914 (Box 20)
    - McClellan, Rousseau, 1914 (Box 20)
    - McNeil, L.H., 1914 (Box 20)
    - Moore, George, 1914 (Box 20)
    - Newcombe, F.C., 1914-1915 (Box 20)
    - Nieuwland, J.A., 1912 (Box 20)
    - Pease, Arthur Stanley (ASP), 1906-1915 (Box 20)
    - Pennell, Francis W., 1914 (Box 20)
    - Pfeiffer, Wanda M., 1915 (Box 20)
    - Piper, C.V., 1914 (Box 20)
    - Potter, Laura, 1906 (Box 20)
    - Potter, Merritt, 1905-1906 (Box 20)
    - Rand, Edward L., undated (Box 20)
    - Reynolds, Ernest S., 1906 (Box 20)
    - Robinson, Benjamin L. (Box 20)
    - Smith, Charles Piper, 1906-1907 (Box 20)
    - Villers, Thomas J., 1905 (Box 20)
    - Wade, Frank B., 1915 (Box 20)
    - Walsh, C. Burton, 1906 (Box 20)
    - Wiggin, Thomas S (Griff), 1906 (Box 20)
  - Photographs, 1891-1978
    The Photographs, 1891-1978 (5.2 linear feet) subseries, arranged by expedition, contains Bartlett's photographic collections from his expeditions in the United States and abroad as well as his personal photographs. These collections include photographic prints, negatives, and film. This subseries is of particular interest to researchers because it documents Bartlett's early ethno botanical research, portraying indigenous societies, archaeology, farming practices, and U-M research practices. The photographs and negatives include substantial metadata, both written on assorted prints and negatives and included in accompanying notebooks or envelopes, directly linking photographs to Bartlett's field notebooks, language materials, and collected specimens. Researchers should note the extensive Sumatra and the Far East collection, which captures Bartlett's multiple trips to the region and research into the Batak peoples of Indonesia.
    - P1: Photograph Album, 1908-1916 (Box 20)
    - P2: Argentina, San Juan, Guayule, 1943
      - Box 1, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Box 1, 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Box 2, 6 folders (Box 21)
    - P3: Central America -- British Honduras, Guatemala, 1931; 3 folders (Box 21)
    - P4: Formosa, 1926-1927; 22 folders (Box 21)
    - P5: Mexico, 1930; 3 folders (Box 22)
    - P6: Panama, 1940 (Box 22)
    - P7: Philippines, 1935
      - Box 1, 19 folders (Box 22)
      - Box 2, 4 folders (Box 23)
    - P8: Sumatra and Far East, 1918-1927
      - Box 1, 1918-1927; 15 folders (Box 23)
      - Box 2, 1918; 6 folders (Box 23)
      - Box 3, 1918; 4 folders (Box 23)
      - Box 4, 1918 (Box 23)
      - File A, Hawaii, Japan, Philippines, China, 1918 (Box 23)
      - File B, Singapore, 1918 (Box 24)
      - File C, Asahan and natives, 1918 (Box 24)
      - File D, Sumatra, 1918 (Box 24)
      - File S, Sumatra, 1927 (Box 24)
      - File 2S, Sumatra, 1927 (Box 24)
      - File 3S, Sumatra, 1927 (Box 24)
    - P9: United States (Michigan) and Canada, 1919-1958; 33 folders (Box 25)
    - P11: Unidentified photographs and negatives, circa 1891-1950 (Box 25)
    - P12: Photographs and negatives, 1918-1978
      - Algae fossil record, undated (Box 25)
      - Allen, Evans S., circa 1920 (Box 25)
      - Cobb, Victor, 1918 (Box 25)
      - Collectors, Thor E. Korsgren and RSS, circa 1945 (Box 25)
      - Edmunds, undated (Box 25)
      - Formosa, 1926-1927; 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Jeffersonia ravine, August 1945 (Box 25)
      - Kauripine, St. Louis, September 20, 1935 (Box 25)
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1920-1945; 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Unidentified and personal, circa 1910-1948; 2 folders (Box 25)
      - U-M Botanical Gardens, 1943-1956 (Box 26)
      - U-M Department of Botany, circa 1978 (Box 26)
  - Special Interests, 1744-1755; 1875-1959
    The Special Interest, 1744-1957 (2.15 linear feet) subseries, arranged alphabetically, documents Bartlett's personal and research interests.2 This subseries provides insight into the history of botany, the history of botany at the University of Michigan, and into ethno botanical research. This series includes Bartlett's research notes, field notes, and Indonesian language materials. This series also contains manuscript histories of botany at the University of Michigan and of the U-M botanical gardens. Also included are materials related to early botany, including a 1550 Cedar of Lebanon census and copies of correspondence by Alexander Garden, Asa Gray, and Edward Lee Greene. [This series is primarily in tact as indexed by the Herbarium; however some material was separated because it was duplicative of records within the Bentley Historical Library's collections.]
    - Abu Nowas, Tales of, undated (Box 26)
    - Address books, 1912-1916 (Box 26)
    - Aerial Photographs for Geographic Surveying (essay), undated (Box 26)
    - Agricultural and Botanical Report on General Region of Bahia Blanca, etc., undated (Box 26)
    - Airplane traverse from Cordoba to Mendoza, undated (Box 26)
    - Alders, undated (Box 26)
    - Algae, undated (Box 26)
    - Allen walnut, circa 1930 (Box 26)
    - Amanita muscaria, 1909 (Box 26)
    - American big trees, 1954 (Box 26)
    - Angiopterius, undated (Box 26)
    - Arboretum -- Nichols Arboretum historical, 1906-1922 (Box 26)
    - Bartram, John letters, 1735-1743 (Box 26)
    - Bessey -- "A Tarantass Trip", 1955 (Box 26)
    - Book Collecting by Botanists, undated (Box 26)
    - Botanical gardens -- history, 1897-1933 (Box 26)
    - Botanical gardens -- special collections, undated (Box 26)
    - Botanists of the American Philosophical Society, undated (Box 26)
    - Botany at the University of Michigan through the First Century circa 1837-1937 manuscript, 1951, 1837-1951 (Box 26)
    - Botanists at the University of Michigan, 1948 (Box 26)
    - Botany as a Career, undated (Box 26)
    - Botany for Stamp Collectors, undated (Box 26)
    - Campbell, Douglas Houghton, undated (Box 26)
    - Cassia gracilipes, undated (Box 26)
    - Cedar of Lebanon, undated (Box 26)
    - Cell and protoplasm, the, botany 1, lecture 1, undated (Box 26)
    - Central American Plants -- Floral Anayses, undated (Box 26)
    - Cinchona -- project proposal Finca el Porvenir, circa 1953 (Box 26)
    - Citizen index -- Proposal for a Master Index of American Citizens, undated (Box 26)
    - Colden, Cadwallder correspondence, 1744-1755 (Box 26)
    - Columbian Institute and National Institute, undated (Box 26)
    - Cycads, undated (Box 26)
    - Dermatoglyphic prints, undated (Box 26)
    - Dioscorea, undated (Box 26)
    - Du Bois, Constance Goddard, 1952 (Box 26)
    - Early American botany, undated (Box 26)
    - Early Botanical Records and Illustrations of Tropical American Economic Plants, undated (Box 26)
    - Early Japanese Knowledge of Loochoo Islands, undated (Box 26)
    - Euphorbia, 1959 (Box 26)
    - Excavation site study, circa 1910 (Box 26)
    - Field Notes, 1906-1944
      - 1906-1907 (Box 26)
      - 1908 (Box 26)
      - 1930 (Box 26)
      - Argentina, 1943-1944 (Box 26)
    - Garden, Alexander correspondence, 1755-65 (Box 26)
    - Greene, Edward Lee (E.L.), 1864-1916
      - Letters, 1872-1911 (Box 26)
      - Manuscript notes and biographical material, 1916 (Box 26)
      - Photographs and clippings, 1864-1915 (Box 26)
    - Guayule in the Big Bend Region of Texas -- Margery Anthony, 1947-1952 (Box 27)
    - Guayule, The Mexican Rubber Plant and the Prospects for a Guayule Industry in Chile and Argentina, report to the 10th Chilean General Science Congress, undated (Box 27)
    - H, J.H.H., 1954 (Box 27)
    - Hasselbring, Heinrich, 1953 (Box 27)
    - History of Botanical Illustration to 1530 by Amy Peterson, 1955 (Box 27)
    - History of Botanical Course, Notes on H.H. Bartlett's by R.C. Williams, 1957 (Box 27)
    - History of Botany in Oregon -- Crater Lake, Highlights of by Richard M. Brown, 1953 (Box 27)
    - History of Russian Botany, undated (Box 27)
    - Impart of Plants for Propagation, undated (Box 27)
    - Juncus, undated (Box 27)
    - Japanese Propaganda Material, undated (Box 27)
    - Legislation, U.S., 1939-1947 (Box 27)
    - Library -- H.H. Bartlett personal library, undated (Box 27)
    - Liliaceae -- Dianella, etc, undated (Box 27)
    - Limnocharis -- tropical, undated (Box 27)
    - Lingnan University, Canton, China, 1947 (Box 27)
    - Linguistic materials, 1918-1955
      - Asahan Plant Names, circa 1918 (Box 27)
      - Asahan II, Ibanag grammar, 1937 (Box 27)
      - Conklin, H.C., Philippines, 1946-1948 (Box 27)
      - Plant names, undated (Box 27)
      - References to the Older Linnaean Literature on Fungi in Linnaeus' Species Plantarium of 1753 Harriett E. Clark, May 28, 1955 (Box 27)
    - Mexico, 1930-1934
      - Maya Area, Preliminary Report on the first Botanical Field Season of the Carnegie-Michigan Survey of the Maya Area, circa 1930 (Box 27)
      - Mexico -- Tamaulipas manuscript notes, circa 1930 (Box 27)
      - Michigan Botanical Excursion -- Charcas, circa 1934 (Box 27)
      - Notebook -- British Honduras and Guatemala, circa 1930 (Box 27)
      - Notebook -- Tropical America miscellaneous notes, circa 1930 (Box 27)
    - Notices of lectures, 1941 (Box 27)
    - Oaks, 1954 (Box 27)
    - Osmotic pressure, undated (Box 27)
    - Paine, J.A., 1912 (Box 27)
    - Palms, undated
      - Daemorps-Draco, undated (Box 27)
      - Notes, undated (Box 27)
      - Notes and photos, undated; 3 folders (Box 27)
      - Old world, undated (Box 27)
      - Sabales of Yucatan, undated (Box 27)
    - Pantheniam, undated (Box 27)
    - Pepper, undated (Box 27)
    - Pestalozzia Guepini Desm, 1921 (Box 27)
    - Philatelic -- The Communist Silver-Yuan Stamps of Swatow, 1951 (Box 27)
    - Philately, circa 1953 (Box 27)
    - Philippines, 1946-1948
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-1948 (Box 28)
      - Early Political Life in the Philippines -- Hayden, J.R., undated (Box 28)
      - Notes on the Waters and Vicinity of Puerto Galera, Mindoro, undated (Box 28)
    - Pitcher, Zina, undated (Box 28)
    - Plant breeders, 1918 (Box 28)
    - Plant collecting by armed forces (Company D), 1944 (Box 28)
    - Plant collecting -- local floras and vegetation surveys, undated (Box 28)
    - Primitive agriculture -- Some words used in connection with primitive agriculture in Southeast Asia, abstract of communication to the Ninth Pacific Science Congress, Bangkok, circa 1957 (Box 28)
    - Pteridophytes of the Maya region, undated (Box 28)
    - Radiation effects, 1912-1950 (Box 28)
      (includes Rogers MacVaugh research notebook)
    - Rubber investigations photograph album, 1941 (Box 28)
    - Ryukwan Airmail Stamps of 1951 and Low Values of the Regular Issue of 1952-1953 Differences among successive Printings and Plates, undated, 1951-1953 (Box 28)
    - Sager, Abram, undated (Box 28)
    - Seed coat pigments -- cowpea, 1912-1913 (Box 28)
    - Sumatra and Malaya, 1929-1933 (Box 28)
    - Sumatra -- Site in Sumatra for large-scale military Aviation operation, undated (Box 28)
    - Types of the U.S. 15 cent stamp of, 1869; circa 1875 (Box 28)
    - Temperature, Brunfels Dutch manuscript transcription, undated (Box 28)
    - Typification of Triletes, undated (Box 28)
    - Voyages -- travels of naturalists: outline of a botanical book-collecting hobby, undated (Box 28)
    - Uncatalogued (miscellaneous), undated (Box 28)
- Herbarium Historical Correspondence Collection, 1851-1971